11. Self-Generated Energy. Imagine a world without batteries or chargers.
What if you could power your electronic devices just by moving around? It's not as crazy as
it sounds. Movement creates energy, and people move all the time. The trick is to collect
that energy and direct it. The idea of creating energy with movement isn't new. Many objects
in the past and the present are charged with cranks, radios, flashlights, or even phone
chargers. You turn the crank for a certain amount of time, and enough energy is created
to power the device. The newest idea is a bit different and a bit more difficult. Instead
of using a specific movement, turning a crank, the idea is to catch and use the energy we
create with our regular movements in our daily life. One way to get this energy is
with an energy harvester designed by Max Donilon. The device fits behind your knee and connects
to the leg muscles. When you walk and move your knee, the movement turns small gears,
which send energy to a generator. The energy could then be used to charge batteries or
even power artificial joints. Another object uses energy from walking in a different way.
The e-bag is a snack cooler. You swing the bag as you carry it. The handle collects the
energy from the swinging motion and uses it to cool the food inside. Some objects have
to be moved to be used. It makes sense to use the energy from moving them to power them,
that's the idea behind a new kinetic mouse. Moving the mouse keeps it powered. Self-generated
and kinetic energy uses are still being developed. As people try to be cleaner and greener,
we can expect to see more objects that depend on our bodies for power.